<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://mdl.life/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mdl.life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do the money come from?</title>
      <link>http://mdl.life/2017-11-14-where-do-the-money-come-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mdl.life/2017-11-14-where-do-the-money-come-from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gateway.ipfs.io/ipfs/QmVHZDTzBb96QgMsCqSEzxuwzyYX4BfNa5M7kxTYWvQC8u/coin.png&#34; alt=&#34;MDL coin&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to keep our financial flows positive we are considering the following methods of revenue creation. Innovative streams are enabled due to the use of blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional Streams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.Extended functionality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will give a chance to be outstanding for our VIP participants. Extended functionality will allow bookers to be more knowledgeable and talents to be more presentable and thus it will make them both more active on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.Commission from transactions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a basic feature of any marketplace and our aim is to make it worth to be. We are not going to charge unreasonable commissions, but instead our aim is to keep them as low as possible, for about 1-2% or even less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.Target advertising&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our platform will consolidate several artistic niches, so it will be perfect place for target advertisement. Although it is important to keep in mind that targeted advertisement is supposed to be as soft as possible. So that only meaningful and engaging materials will be allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Innovative Streams&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reputation-based partnership programs with brands
Talents are special. They are more than average because of their skills, appearance, and personality. People look at them more often. So why don’t they get a discount on some products or services and became a live advertisement? The higher the talent reputation, the higher the discount! Credibility of talent reputation is powered by blockchain technology and transactions are supported with MDL Token. This is advertisment sharing.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://gateway.ipfs.io/ipfs/QmXYFsWZ6xD8x1JoHW4XTisgURXJbtTd2XrM2n2UNPkWHb/partnership.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MDL Partnership&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prosumer ecosystem marketplace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often talents use extremely customised equipment or costumes which is not possible to find in ordinal shops, so they create themselves! Crafted costumes, equipment, supplies and else are all tradable/rentable commodities and on our MDL platform it will be so easy to get involved in these market relations using MDL token.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://gateway.ipfs.io/ipfs/QmYkMaUN76r9uwsDbBTPXEjKcQ2tD5MjqK8utdbzQSrdy2/ecosystem.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MDL Ecosystem&#34; /&gt;
  3. Live broadcasting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life of talents is unusual - every new event is like an adventure. So why don’t show it to others and get paid a bit? Payments will be supported by MDL Token. With deducted commission of course.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://gateway.ipfs.io/ipfs/QmaQKVcmPzuJ7GU1o7hvQ267q2iNEc2AcTgzgXqbur8dDk/broadcasting.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MDL Broadcasting&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What we gonna do?</title>
      <link>http://mdl.life/2017-10-30-what-we-gonna-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mdl.life/2017-10-30-what-we-gonna-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gateway.ipfs.io/ipfs/QmVqUgtsLLuUmLfEJSpejr36LFmSpnGsBLVKVj28tCkege/MDL%20Explained.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MDL Explained&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert Einstein — &amp;lsquo;If I had an hour to solve a problem I&amp;rsquo;d spend 55 minutes thinking about the problem and 5 minutes thinking about solutions.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That barely applies to constantly evolving talent market that requires nonstop monitoring and analysis in order to be aware of constantly popping up issues. In addition, solutions are not coming immediately so that certain complications remain simply ignored. Thus not only identification of existing issues, but also foreseeing of upcoming ones and consequent implementation of preventive measures will allow one to be on the top of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding of business processes in talent market as well as ability to utilize contemporary technological solutions allows our team to become a game changer in the industry. Our tools will help to resolve existing issues and make live for conscientious market participants better.
Specifically, we are going to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As insiders in the industry we are able to determine and develop simple instruments for both bookers and talents, such as easy-to-use booking system, appealing talent profiles, time-management tools, talent catalogs for final clients, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By providing useful tools for both talents and bookers we will consolidate existing market on one platform, so that the search for talents and jobs will be much simplified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With help of blockchain technology we are going to establish solid rating system for every participant and thus bring transparency and credibility to the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When developing the platform we are going to employ iterative approach so that our tools will be constantly evolving according to the market conditions and needs. The cornerstone of this endeavor is our philosophy – provide more efficiency and transparency to benefit society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gateway.ipfs.io/ipfs/Qmes4y4RJ2LQot6i3sYoc2QDyhxs4RqHEMHVQBEfjs8V5q/Market%20problems%20solved.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Problems solved&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MDL team at Slush</title>
      <link>http://mdl.life/2017-10-13-MDL-team-Slush-Shanghai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mdl.life/2017-10-13-MDL-team-Slush-Shanghai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmcN4PPiFfizycvjp5xteL2RPjresxXCau51USXifKLcdP&#34; alt=&#34;Slush Shanghai&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first public appearance of MDL was on the 12th of October 2017 at Slush Conference. We have presented our vision and ideas to several experienced VC investors and high-tech businessman and not only got positive feedback and encouragement but also received some valuable advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent ideas cannot appear in reserved ecosystem, so sharing thinking and knowledge is absolutely important for survival and development in modern world. It is said that social capital is much more important than any physical asset, so we were very happy to grow up our network by acquiring new valuable connections as well as strengthen our ties with old friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MDL team is exposing its deepest gratitude to Slush crew for such a smooth organization of this inspiring event and absolutely hopes to see everyone later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmWuLRdCaiGCN2ko5fAFjHk8uwnvFMFH2j5HCPojPu7GKQ&#34; alt=&#34;MDL Team&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MDL inception (video)</title>
      <link>http://mdl.life/2017-10-10-MDL-inception/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mdl.life/2017-10-10-MDL-inception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;video width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;https://ipfs.io/ipfs/QmeqKazV19qNmysr6yfuxmVujN2wq6fzJqZUZhqSSCRo46&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is said that some events have less probability to happen and some more. It looks like the event that took place on the 8th of October had pretty good chances to appear. All the puzzle pieces were collected in one place. It was a tiny step of initiation towards a great venture that is going to affect our society and even much more the lives of its direct stakeholders who were three…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three friends from former Russian capital of Saint-Petersburg living in Shanghai and working in different industries – IT, international trade, and TVC production. The only thing that they had in common besides their nationality is a sparkling spirit of undertaking. And that was enough to begin…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But cut the pathetic shit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pretty straightforward – the idea to join blockchain tsunami that is going to flood every economy sector in the nearest future was well-weighted and we have determined ourselves to be the first in the market we know, which is foreign model/artists segment of event and production industries. We have agreed that the combination of IT and blockchain expertise, market understanding and experience, legal and tax know-how gives us sound competitive advantage and excellent opportunity to shake the market disruptively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few words about us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roman Tronenko.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Experienced Fullstack Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the internet industry. IPFS pioneer. Polyglot in all senses: Skilled in Golang, Python, C++, Java, Kotlin, Ruby, and eager to learn more. Strong engineering professional with two Master&amp;rsquo;s degrees focused in Computer Science. The founder and initiator of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gogo.tattoo&#34;&gt;gogo.tattoo&lt;/a&gt; Project. If you had to do something with China, Mandarin language or languages in general, there&amp;rsquo;s a very big chance you&amp;rsquo;ve used one of the apps Roman built or was involved in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dmitry Timokhin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Graduated from St. Petersburg State University, Russia he is living in Shanghai, PRC more than a decade. The area of expertise including but not limited to the apparel manufacturing, media publishing house, food and non-food import/export and distribution, biomedicine technologies and regenerative medicine. Dmitry runs a group of companies set in China, Vietnam, Hong Kong, Taiwan and Russia, which makes him able to handle any sort of tax and legal issues in Asia as well as be experienced enough in scaling strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dimitry Doronin.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Being European educated he is actively developing his professional career in China for about 5 year. While pursuing his PhD degree in team management and team creativity he is actively involved in TVC production as a production coordinator and casting manager. Being a model on part-time basis himself on the top of that gives him excellent observation point to evaluate the overall talent industry in China and worldwide. Initiator and COO of F You Art Community and several other smaller media projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each one of us this project is an important step forward within our careers and we all feel enthusiastic and prepared for the long-term sailing, for the storms and the calms that are going to happen on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we have started. Started to discuss, plan, learn, execute and have fun together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MDL was the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it has begun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The thing is</title>
      <link>http://mdl.life/2017-10-08-the-thing-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mdl.life/2017-10-08-the-thing-is/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As majority of Asian countries, including China and Indonesia, are already for several years enthusiastically transforming their economies from export-driven to consumption-driven, advertisement industry is continuing to show double digits growth. Taking into consideration collectivistic patterns of Asian cultures we can observe overwhelming involvement of talents in all marketing activities. No matter whether it is online, onscreen, or onsite promotion, talents are always the key part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, for an instance, China is experiencing a massive influx of foreign talents of all types – models and actors, singers and dancers, circus and theme parks performers, and all of them are considered premium here just because of their nationality. It is estimated that there are about 10.000 foreign models working on freelance basis in Mainland China along with more than 30 professional model agencies supplying talents for event companies, production houses, exhibitions, and else. As that all started to happen just recently, there is no any solid infrastructure and established market standards for participants’ interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success of a promotional event, TVC shooting, or a fashion show highly depends on talents involved. When a big amount of resource is concentrated to push forward a product or an idea it is absolutely necessary to be sure that talents will do their best. From another hand, talents are often misused, cheated, or simply treated bad. That’s why it might be difficult and costly to establish cooperation with professional and well-behaved models, actors, and other type of artists, until they are sure that everything will go well.
Since the market is continuing to grow there is a sound call for regulations and transparency coming from both sides - bookers and talents.  More particularly, there are the following problems existing within talent-booker relations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Spreading job info is resource consuming and it is difficult to find decent talents. The current supply and demand is hidden, channels are not consolidated. Bookers are not aware of talents schedule, so it takes time to contact each one. The current solutions are outdated technologically and logically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reputation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Tracking talent and bookers blacklist is difficult, since there is no unified database for that. Often job conditions are not described clearly, rude or lie from bookers. No fixed price for jobs, a lot of money cutting and low offers from the bookers. Models often misbehave or cheat their parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Presentation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Collecting and presenting casting info is time-consuming. The final client often goes for talents with just better presentation materials instead of taking the better talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the market is getting mature and more sophisticated there is a certain need for complex monitoring and preventive measures that would help to make the industry more transparent and efficient. Generally, the problems in Asian talent market are quite common for all developing markets. Thus once the solution is found and successfully introduced, it can be applied to other regions as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>